# Hassan Ali

PhD Candidate, UNSW, Sydney

➤ hassan.ali@unsw.edu.au

Google Scholar

Sydney, Australia

**(b)** 0000-0002-1701-0390

nassanalikhatim

hassanalikhatim.github.io

## How do I see myself?

I am a self-motivated machine learning engineer and researcher. As a researcher, I strive to enable real-world deployment of machine learning models that people can trust. As an engineer, I want to use my machine learning skills to assist people in their daily routine tasks.

## **Education**

Sep 2023 – Ongoing

## University of New South Wales (UNSW), Sydney, Australia

PhD in Computer Science and Engineering

• Research focuses on Trustworthy Machine Learning

Sep 2017 – Aug 2019

# National University of Sciences and Technology (NUST), Islamabad, Pakistan

Master of Science in Electrical Engineering (CGPA: 4.0/4.0)

• <u>Thesis Title:</u> "Analyzing the Security Vulnerabilities of Deep Neural Networks: Attacks and Defenses"

Sep 2013 - Aug 2017

# University of Engineering and Technology (UET), Lahore, Pakistan

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering (CGPA: 3.645/4.0)

# **Work Experience**

Feb 2024 - Present

# University of New South Wales (UNSW)

Casual Research Assistant

Large Language Models

Sep 2021 - Sep 2023

### **Information Technology University (ITU)**

Research Assistant

• Human-centric Robust ML-driven IoT Smart Services

Jan 2021 - Nov 2021

## **Information Technology University (ITU)**

Research Assistant

Mitigating Anti-social Behavior through Beneficial AI

### Tools and skillset

- Python, PyTorch, TensorFlow (last 5 years)
- Java, C, MATLAB, Verilog, VHDL, HTML

# **Publications**

2024

1. Al-Maliki, S., Qayyum, A., **Ali, H.**, Abdallah, M., Qadir, J., Hoang, D. T., Niyato, D. & Al-Fuqaha, A. Adversarial Machine Learning for Social Good: Reframing the Adversary as an Ally. *IEEE Transactions on Artificial Intelligence* (2024).

- 2. **Ali, H.**, Butt, M. A., Filali, F., Al-Fuqaha, A. & Qadir, J. Consistent Valid Physically-Realizable Adversarial Attack Against Crowd-Flow Prediction Models. *IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems*, 1–16. doi:10.1109/TITS.2023.3343971 (2023).
- 3. **Ali, H.**, Khan, M. S., AlGhadhban, A., Alazmi, M., Alzamil, A., Al-utaibi, K. & Qadir, J. Con-detect: Detecting adversarially perturbed natural language inputs to deep classifiers through holistic analysis. *Computers & Security* **125**, 103367 (2023).
- 4. Butt, M. A., Qayyum, A., **Ali, H.**, Al-Fuqaha, A. & Qadir, J. Towards secure private and trustworthy human-centric embedded machine learning: An emotion-aware facial recognition case study. *Computers & Security* **125**, 103058 (2023).
- 5. Qayyum, A., Butt, M. A., **Ali, H.**, Usman, M., Halabi, O., Al-Fuqaha, A., Abbasi, Q. H., Imran, M. A. & Qadir, J. Secure and Trustworthy Artificial Intelligence-Extended Reality (AI-XR) for Metaverses. *ACM Comput. Surv.* (2023).
- 6. **Ali, H.**, Khan, M. S., Al-Fuqaha, A. & Qadir, J. Tamp-X: Attacking explainable natural language classifiers through tampered activations. *Computers & Security* **120**, 102791 (2022).
- 7. **Ali, H.**, Khan, M. S., AlGhadhban, A., Alazmi, M., Alzamil, A., Al-Utaibi, K. & Qadir, J. All your fake detector are belong to us: evaluating adversarial robustness of fake-news detectors under black-box settings. *IEEE Access* 9, 81678–81692 (2021).
  - 8. Petrick, N., Akbar, S., Cha, K. H., Nofech-Mozes, S., Sahiner, B., Gavrielides, M. A., Kalpathy-Cramer, J., Drukker, K., Martel, A. L. & BreastPathQ Challenge Group, f. t. SPIE-AAPM-NCI BreastPathQ Challenge: an image analysis challenge for quantitative tumor cellularity assessment in breast cancer histology images following neoadjuvant treatment. *Journal of Medical Imaging* 8, 034501–034501 (2021).
- 9. Khalid, F., **Ali, H.**, Hanif, M. A., Rehman, S., Ahmed, R. & Shafique, M. FaDec: A Fast Decision-based Attack for Adversarial Machine Learning in 2020 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN) (2020), 1–8.
- 2019 10. **Ali, H.**, Khalid, F., Tariq, H. A., Hanif, M. A., Ahmed, R. & Rehman, S. SSCNets: Robustifying DNNs using Secure Selective Convolutional Filters. *IEEE Design & Test* 37, 58–65 (2019).
  - 11. Khalid, F., **Ali, H.**, Tariq, H., Hanif, M. A., Rehman, S., Ahmed, R. & Shafique, M. *QuSecNets: Quantization-based defense mechanism for securing deep neural network against adversarial attacks* in 2019 IEEE 25th International Symposium on On-Line Testing and Robust System Design (IOLTS) (2019), 182–187.